<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Thom Wiggers</title><link>/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Thom Wiggers</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 -- CC-BY 4.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using (post-quantum) KEMs in TLS 1.3</title><link>/post/kems_in_tls_1.3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 09:34:44 +0200</pubDate><guid>/post/kems_in_tls_1.3/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The new TLS 1.3 standard [1] does not yet provide any support for
post-quantum algorithms. In this blog post we&amp;rsquo;ll be talking about how we
could negotiate a post-quantum key exchange using a (post-quantum) Key
Encapsulation Mechanism (KEM). In the NIST Standardisation effort [2],
many KEMs are currently under consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Latincrypt paper!</title><link>/post/2017-08-24-latincrypt_paper/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 20:35:33 +0200</pubDate><guid>/post/2017-08-24-latincrypt_paper/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m going to Cuba as my submission to Latincrypt 2017 was accepted! The paper is called Energy-efficient ARM64 Cluster with Cryptanalytic Applications: 80 cores that do not cost you an ARM and a leg. Visit the accompanying page to view the software. I&amp;rsquo;ll upload the paper once I&amp;rsquo;m done editing.</description></item><item><title>Securing OpenSSH</title><link>/post/2016-01-29-securing_openssh/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 16:27:03 +0100</pubDate><guid>/post/2016-01-29-securing_openssh/</guid><description>You can set up SSH to prefer Elliptic Curve cryptography over RSA, and use modern key exchange algorithms without exposing yourself to Logjam-style attacks. It&amp;rsquo;s also good to get rid of SHA1 and MD5.
A good resource is the OpenSSH Guidelines page on the Mozilla wiki. You can basically copy the config.
Caveat: I found out that the version of Paramiko in Debian Jessie does not support SHA2 hashes or ECC in the key exchange.</description></item><item><title>Prøst at Student Research Conference</title><link>/post/2015-11-15-proest_at_student_research_conference/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2015 15:32:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/2015-11-15-proest_at_student_research_conference/</guid><description>In July, Peter Schwabe, who supervised my Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s thesis project, suggested to submit my work to the Student Research Conference. It then turned out that the deadline was the next day, so I had to work hard to convert 28 pages of thesis into a paper of 4 pages.
To my own suprise my paper was accepted for a poster presentation. It was very interesting and challenging to tell the people at the conference (which was at Tilburg University) about my research: I had a very technical story, and a lot of people in the humanities already are scared by the word &amp;ldquo;encryption&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin private key qrcode scraper</title><link>/post/2015-11-01-bitcoin_private_key_qrcode_scraper/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 21:28:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/2015-11-01-bitcoin_private_key_qrcode_scraper/</guid><description>Tegenlicht today had an episode about Bitcoin where they announced they were going to give away €100 in Bitcoin. They were going to put up a Bitcoin wallet private key as a QR-code on the screen.
It seemed to me like a fun project to try and grab that Bitcoin. I coded an app that takes a screenshot every couple seconds and then tries to detect all QR-codes in it. If any of the codes look like a private key, I then used the Blockcypher API to determine the balance and empty the account into my own wallet.</description></item><item><title>Deprecating fields in MongoEngine Documents</title><link>/post/2015-07-26-deprecating_fields_in_mongoengine_documents/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2015 17:01:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/2015-07-26-deprecating_fields_in_mongoengine_documents/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had to rename some fields today with MongoEngine. Using the
following approach, I was able to raise &lt;code&gt;DeprecationWarning&lt;/code&gt;s
when old version were used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create the following function. It returns a property that will access
the new variable name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Prøst</title><link>/post/2015-04-25-pr%C3%B8st/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 14:39:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/2015-04-25-pr%C3%B8st/</guid><description>Prøst is an authenticated encryption cipher and a contestant in the CAESAR competition for Authenticated Encryption. For my bachelor thesis research project, I&amp;rsquo;ve implemented Prøst on ARM11.
You can find more information about this project on this page.</description></item><item><title>Globally install powerline</title><link>/post/2014-09-25-globally_install_powerline/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 23:50:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/2014-09-25-globally_install_powerline/</guid><description>Today I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to globally install Powerline. That was a bit of a pain because it has no global config files.
Quick and dirty how-to:
Add XDG_CONFIG_DIRS=/etc/xdg to /etc/environment if it isn&amp;rsquo;t already set, Copy the config to /etc/xdg/powerline, Customize config, Load powerline from /etc/bash.bashrc, ~/.zshrc, etc. My config can be found at on Github</description></item><item><title>Perfect forward secrecy and HSTS with nginx</title><link>/post/2014-08-07-perfect_forward_secrecy_with_nginx/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2014 19:30:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/2014-08-07-perfect_forward_secrecy_with_nginx/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today, I enabled perfect forward secrecy on my &lt;code&gt;nginx&lt;/code&gt; installation. I&amp;rsquo;m writing
down the config so I can easily find it later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Dave Eggers – The Circle</title><link>/post/2014-08-05-the_circle/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 17:43:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/2014-08-05-the_circle/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I recently read &lt;em&gt;The Circle&lt;/em&gt; by Dave Eggers. It is a bit like the classic
dystopian novel 1984 being brought up to date in the age of smartphones, apps
and Google, Facebook and Twitter. Though it does not have very novel ideas,
Eggers paints a picture of the tyranny of the masses and of the consequences of
a society that only has a surface level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Blendle</title><link>/post/2014-05-01-blendle/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 15:50:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/2014-05-01-blendle/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http//blendle.nl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Blendle&lt;/a&gt; is een kort geleden gelanceerde website waarop je digitaal door
kranten en tijdschriften kan bladeren. Denk je &amp;ldquo;goh, dit wil ik wel lezen&amp;rdquo;, dan
kun je met één klik het artikel openen en tegen betaling van zo&amp;rsquo;n € 0,10 het
artikel lezen. Dit alles in een simpele, maar heel effectieve website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Jekyll</title><link>/post/2014-04-30-jekyll/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 17:44:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/2014-04-30-jekyll/</guid><description>As you can see, this site has been overhauled! I am now using the pretty awesome Jekyll static site generator.
The source of my website is on Github.</description></item><item><title>Time-invariant equality in assembly</title><link>/post/2014-03-21-time-invariant-equality-in-assembly/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 18:25:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>/post/2014-03-21-time-invariant-equality-in-assembly/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;For crypto code it&#39;s important that it&#39;s time-invariant, otherwise it is
vulnerable to timing attacks. I&#39;ve had to build this time-invariant equality
test from scratch, because I couldn&#39;t find something on Google. I hope it&#39;s
useful to someone else. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Keybase.io</title><link>/post/2014-03-16-keybase-io/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2014 13:12:27 +0100</pubDate><guid>/post/2014-03-16-keybase-io/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Users of PGP will be aware of the many keyservers around the web. &lt;a
href=&#34;http://keybase.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Keybase.io&lt;/a&gt; has launched as an
interesting alternative to the &#39;boring&#39; and complicated keyservers. They provide
an easy CLI client and web client (if you choose to share your private key
- I didn&#39;t) for PGP crypto, where you don&#39;t need to know someone&#39;s key id - just
their username on Twitter or GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>TextSecure</title><link>/post/2014-02-25-textsecure/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2014 01:51:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>/post/2014-02-25-textsecure/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Instead of trusting Telegram (which is a bad idea, try using Google for a few
minutes, or &lt;a
href=&#34;http://unhandledexpression.com/2013/12/17/telegram-stand-back-we-know-maths/&#34;&gt;start&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thoughtcrime.org/blog/telegram-crypto-challenge/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)
I&#39;m going to bet on TextSecure, which actually does something other
cryptographers agree with..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Music Review</title><link>/post/2013-09-29-music-review/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2013 21:00:42 +0200</pubDate><guid>/post/2013-09-29-music-review/</guid><description>It&#39;s been a while since I posted. Today I decided it was time to behave myself a bit like the pretentious hipster I secretly am and post a bit about the music that I discovered lately.
London Grammar - If You Wait (2013) London Grammar are an UK based indie pop band. They released their debut album If You Wait a couple of weeks ago. Pitchfork already wrote a great review about them, so I&#39;m not going to repeat that, but I&#39;d like to highlight their great cover of Kavinsky&#39;s Nightcall, capturing the feeling of the original track so nicely.</description></item><item><title>OpenSC, Gentoo &amp; Feitian ePass 2003</title><link>/post/2013-05-25-opensc-gentoo-feitian-epass-2003/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 22:29:55 +0200</pubDate><guid>/post/2013-05-25-opensc-gentoo-feitian-epass-2003/</guid><description>While playing with my ePass2003 on my Gentoo installation today, I had some trouble getting it to work. As it turned out, you need the following use flags enabled:
# /etc/portage/package.use dev-libs/opensc pcsc-lite secure-messaging Hope this helps someone.</description></item><item><title>Certificate signing with an ePass2003</title><link>/post/2014-06-10-certificate-signing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/2014-06-10-certificate-signing/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I have a fairly creative ssl setup on my webserver:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I run my own &amp;lsquo;certificate authority&amp;rsquo; which signs the server certificate;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have a bunch of alternative names specified;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The CA certificate sits on an ePass 2003 PKI token.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m writing down how I sign certificates in this context so I can use this to
look up the procedure instead of spending hours in DuckDuckGo. This is more of
a tutorial than elegant prose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>